They say they feel more
comfortable with full invisibility.
Though I wouldn't say I prefer
being fully invisible myself.
EPISODE 11: THE INVISIBLE PERSON VILLAGE
The next stop is Third
District Shopping Street.
Third District Shopping Street.
Akira-san?
Are you all right?
Oh, I'm fine.
I'm sorry we had to
make so many transfers.
My hometown is really out there.
No problem!
I'm excited to visit
the invisible person village!
It's in the middle of nowhere.
Nothing but fields.
It's very closed off, too.
Oh, really?
Well, it's a rather odd village.
An odd village?
THIRD DISTRICT SHOPPING STREET
The air is so fresh!
Yes, it's a serene, green place.
This is the shopping street.
I see. It's very lively!
Are these all the locals?
I sense so many people!
I should have expected that.
The village is exempted
from certain laws,
so we're allowed to walk around
with full invisibility.
Many of the invisible people who live
here go around like that all the time.
I see!
Is the people being fully invisible
what makes the town odd?
Well, it disorients a lot of people,
but I suppose it's
an everyday thing for you.
Oh, my family's house is up ahead.
Are you all right, Shizuka-san?
I-I just got really nervous!
I know how you feel,
but I know you can handle it.
Y-Yes! I'll do my best!
Is that... Aki?
TONOME
I'm home!
Shizuka-san.
Sitting to your left is my father.
To your right is my mother.
I-It's so quiet.
Akira-san's always quiet,
but they're even quieter.
It's like... a silent pressure...
What is it?
Um... My name is Shizuka Yako!
Akira-san is always helping me... um...
I-It's so good to meet you!
Yes.
Thank you for helping our Akira.
Her voice is so flat and impersonal.
Maybe she doesn't like me?
Wh-What do I do, Akira-san?
We're currently dating
and considering living together.
R-Right to the point?!
Sounds fine to me.
Yes, it sounds fine.
Also, I've been wondering...
Why are you wearing those strange masks?
Huh? Masks?
You said you'd be bringing
another species by.
We thought she'd be more
comfortable if we had faces.
Shizuka-san is blind.
They're not doing much good.
Ah, fair point.
Yes, fair point.
I thought I told you that.
I guess she can't tell.
Yes, I guess she can't tell.
Well, this might be okay!
Is it all right if we
turn fully invisible, then?
Yes, that's fine.
They say they feel more
comfortable with full invisibility.
Yes. That's the case
for all invisible people.
Really?
Fully invisible is how we
should rightly be, after all.
I should take her to meet
Grandmother next, I suppose.
She's in her room because of her bad leg.
Though I wouldn't say I prefer
being fully invisible myself.
Because you like people
to see your favorite outfits, right?
Later, can I tell you all
the details of the suit I'm wearing now?
I'd love to hear it!
Grandma, we're coming in.
Welcome!
Grandma, Shizuka-san is...
Well, I told them to let you know, too!
Oh!
In the Warring States period,
we were a house of ninja
who served our lord well!
Ninja!
You were ninja?! That's amazing!
We have shuriken
and such in the warehouse!
C-Can you do ninjutsu?!
Our fully invisible forms certainly
seemed like ninjutsu to outsiders!
But we couldn't make our shuriken
and other tools invisible,
so we had to use various other tricks!
I-I see!
She's very excited.
So cool! So cool!
Akira.
Hey. It's been a while, Aki.
Kiriguro-san! You're back in town?!
That's my line.
Hey, you've come a long way.
I guess I was still in school
the last time we talked...
You were such a little kid.
You surprised me,
dressed up in that suit.
I'm impressed you could
tell it was me, really.
Who's that?
This is Masashi Kiriguro.
Do you remember the story I told you?
The first invisible person model...
Oh, that one!
What kind of introduction is that?
We were just talking old times.
I retired from modeling.
Now I run this Italian place.
You surprised me, though.
I was opening the place up this morning
and thought, "Hey, is that Aki?"
I'm impressed you recognized me.
It's been over ten years.
Not many people around here
who don't do full invisibility.
I just kinda figured.
Here, eat up.
It smells wonderful!
Thank you for the food.
Did you recognize me, Aki?
I didn't have all this ink
the last time we met.
I knew you on sight.
When you were a child, you drew
the patterns on with a pen, right?
Oh, right.
Guess I haven't changed much either.
But you were such a help to me then.
Oh, I remember!
You were crying your eyes out.
"I dunno who anyone is!"
Come on, you don't have to
bring up that part!
You were crying?
I grew up surrounded by other species.
When I was first brought
to this village when I was young...
Oh, you're all alone?
Come over here! I've got some candy!
Being surrounded by invisible people
at all times frightened me...
What a cutie-pie!
Hey, now!
And then I met Kiriguro-san,
who had drawn on his face.
You came from the big city, right?
I thought, is this kid holding
a one-man Halloween?
Hey. Lay off.
I thought you were such a strange child.
But you really set me at ease.
Thinking back now,
I drew a lot of different
things on my face.
Not sure how I made it as a model.
At the time, he modeled fashions
as the first invisible model.
I see! He did!
Back then, pretty much
the only jobs for invisible people
were secret agent stuff
or stuff here at home.
I was curious about the big city,
so I packed a bag and went there.
Huh?
There's never been
an invisible person model before...
I can see some appeal in showing
off the outfit's lining...
Could be pretty cool.
But only for a moment.
A moment's intrigue, and then it's over.
I mean, if invisibility's
all you're offering,
I could get any invisible person.
Why does it have to be you?
Dammit. Another audition down the drain.
Why it has to me...
What, did I hit you?!
That hurt...
Roll your sleeves down! It's not safe!
True enough.
See you later!
Later!
I mean, if invisibility's
all you're offering,
I could get any invisible person.
Roll your sleeves down! It's not safe!
No wonder the people back home
didn't want me to go to the city.
Life here is too damn hard
for invisible people.
If invisibility's all you're offering,
I could get any invisible person.
I can't tell anything if I can't see you!
What are you even thinking?
Don't you run away!
You came here because you wanted to!
You should've stayed home
and lived a normal life!
It's your fault for leaving!
I feel sick.
Crap. Big audition today...
Gotta hurry...
What the hell did I do?!
Shit, shit, shit!
I've got my audition coming up!
No freaking way!
So...
I'm sorry for coming
to the audition looking ridiculous.
Dammit.
Just reject me already.
You're really interesting.
Oh, yeah...
The "moment's intrigue" thing, right?
No, you're incredibly interesting.
You're in.
You tattooed a skeleton on yourself
and added body paint to match
whatever design you were wearing.
People loved the way it made
the clothing stand out.
I can't imagine it at all!
It made the clothing stand out, so I got
calls to model all sorts of collections.
Invisible people tend to get lumped
all together because we can't be seen,
but thinking back now,
the body paint and tattoos were
my own way of expressing myself.
EXPRESSING MYSELF
It's the only way I can
express myself, after all.
Expressing myself...
They're so similar.
Hey,
don't the people of the village struggle
with everyone being
invisible all the time?
Invisible people have an organ that
lets them sense other invisible people.
We can sense where they are,
and tell who's who.
But the organ that makes
it possible tends to end up
underdeveloped in those
who are raised in the city, like me.
I was around elementary
school age when I learned
to identify people by their
unique sounds and smells.
Is that you, Ema-chan?
How did you know?!
It seems like other people can't do that,
so it always really surprised them.
I see.
I suppose we all adjust
to our surroundings.
And since I was raised
among non-invisible people...
Yes,
the reason I learned how to do it isn't
because I worked really hard at it,
or that other people
don't work hard at it...
I was just living my life, being blind,
and I guess I adjusted to the need.
I know exactly what you mean.
But...
Because of that, I was able to find you.
So I'm glad!
Hey, could you take that somewhere else?
Later.
Thank you for the meal!
Aki, make sure you
stop by again sometime.
Yes, I will.
Invisible people tend to
be judged by their invisibility.
We're treasured because we can't be seen.
Suspected because
we can't be seen.
Feared.
And ignored.
But that didn't matter to Shizuka-san.
Shizuka-san.
Yes?
I'm so glad I met you.
I-It's not that big a deal...
It's just how I feel right now.
You're always so frank!
Well, I'm an invisible person...
I can't express my feelings
if I don't say them.
Hearing that... makes my heart race...
All the little things you say
and do make my heart race.
You liar!
I'm not lying.
Good, just in time.
Hey, Sis.
Fu-kun!
Why did you want to come all of a sudden?
Where's Tonome-san?
He's not walking you home after work?
He's still working!
Detective work doesn't
have hard and fast hours!
Oh.
Anyway, I'm hungry.
Take me somewhere good to eat.
But it's not payday yet...
Dad gave me 10,000 yen for dinner.
Then off we go!
I've got some places
registered in my guidance app...
What's wrong?
There's an invisible
person wearing a suit.
It could be Tonome-san.
Akira-san's nearby?!
I'll check if it's him.
Check if it's him?
Here.
Tonome-san...
Thank you so much!
Sis.
Welcome back!
Well? Was it him?
Tonome is a traitor.
I'm gonna bash him good.
What are you talking about?
Honestly. Tailing Akira-san...
He's a detective. He'll notice you!
He's the one sneaking around.
I'll whack him either way.
It's probably a marriage scam.
Akira-san would never
do something like that.
And you haven't done enough investigation
to confirm that he's cheating.
No, I saw him give her the ring.
Goodness me. You're such
an amateur, Fu-kun.
Don't forget that I'm an employee
at a detective agency myself!
You're an amateur too.
You're not a detective.
They went into a building.
Are you nervous?
Yes, very.
Fu-kun, where are you?!
Don't leave me behind!
Is this glass? A window?!
Come on, Fu-kun!
Shizuka-san, right this way.
A-Akira-san?
I forgot.
Um... fancy meeting you here.
I'm sorry, but I'm working right now.
Can we talk later?
Working?
Um, I'm sorry to interrupt, but...
Big Brother?
I've been looking for you for so long...
It's been twenty years...
I finally found you!
How have you been?!
I'm okay!
Really?!
Shall we give them some privacy?
How about dinner?